Office of the President Mary Maples Dunn Files, 1985-1995
Smith College Archives
- SERIES XV. NON-SMITH ORGANIZATIONS, (9 document boxes / 3.8 linear feet)
  - Massachusetts Department of Education 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Massachusetts Department of Education 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Massachusetts Education Loan Authority 1988 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Massachusetts Industrial Finance Agency 1988 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - National Association of Independent Colleges and Universities [NAICU] 1985-1988 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - National Association of Independent Colleges and Universities 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - National Association of Independent Colleges and Universities 1991-1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association [NCAA] 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - New England Association of Schools and Colleges [NEASC]
    - -General 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - -General 1989-1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - -Accreditation 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - -Accreditation Jan-Aug 1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - -Accreditation Sep-Dec 1987 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - -Accreditation-Report on Institutional Self-Study Sep 1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - -Reaccreditation Committee 1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - New England Board of Higher Education 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - New England Colleges Fund 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - New England Colleges Fund 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - New England Colleges Fund 1990-1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Open Society Scholars Fund 1986-1990 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Pew Higher Education Roundtable 1992-1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Some Corporate and Foundation Relations Officers [SCAFRO] 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Tillman Institute of Human Relations 1988-1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - United Way 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - United Way 1987 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - United Way 1988 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - United Way 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - United Way 1991 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - United Way 1992 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - United Way 1993-1995 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Women Presidents' Group 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - World Affairs Council 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Xerox Corporation 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous
    - -A-B ca. 1985-1995 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - -C-G ca. 1985-1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - -H-N ca. 1985-1995 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - -O-Z ca. 1985-1995 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- SERIES XVI. SPEECHES, (2 document boxes / 0.8 linear feet)
  The records in this series are filed chronologically by event and are labeled with one or all of the following: title, location, and event.
  The duties of the President included many public speaking engagements, not only at Smith College events but also at local and national gatherings. The records in this series include notes and some full texts for many of these speeches, as well as associated correspondence and newspaper clippings.
  More detailed information about the events themselves can be found in the Events and Engagements series, and in some cases in the records of sponsoring Smith Administrative Offices, Academic Departments, Committees and Boards, or Non-Smith Organizations.
  - January All-College Meetings 1987-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Last Chapels 1986-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Opening Convocations 1985-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Parents Speeches 1985-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - State of the College Addresses 1986-1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Macalester College 7 Nov 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ethel Walker School 28 Apr 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Westchester Smith Club - "Some Themes in the Education of Women" May 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Scripps College 11 Oct 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Marietta College - "The Education of Women in the 21st Century" 11 Feb 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Teaching For Tomorrow 21 Apr 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 7 Colleges Alumnae Seminar - "The Education Conundrum" 14 Oct 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - School for Social Work 23 Jul 1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Smith All-College Meeting on Race 1 May 1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Saint Edward's School 5 June 1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clarke School for the Deaf 18 June 1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - National Association of Principals of Schools for Girls 22 Feb 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Council for Women in Independent Schools 19 Apr 1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Dwight-Englewood School 6 June 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous 1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Notes & Sources ca. 1985-1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- SERIES XVII. STUDENTS, (3 document boxes / 1.3 linear feet)
  The records in this series document the relationship of the Smith student body with the faculty and administration of the college. There are records about student organizations, publications, athletics, and other activities.
  Information about students can also be found in the records of Committees and Boards with student representation, in the Administrative Offices series in the records of the Dean of the College and the Dean of Students, as well as in the records of specific student residences in the Buildings and Grounds series.
  - General 1985-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academic Awards
    - -Eleanor Flexner Prize 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - -Hamm Prize 1986-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - -Knowles Scholarship 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - -Sean McFarland Prize 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - -Miscellaneous 1991, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Athletics
    See also Series IX. Committees & Boards-Committee to Review the Athletic Department and the Department of Exercise and Sport Studies
    - -General 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - -General 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - -General 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - -General 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - -General 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - -General 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - -Budget 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - -Meeting Agendas 1988-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - -NCAA Self-Study 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - -Basketball 1986-1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - -Crew 1985-1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - -Field Hockey 1985, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - -Gymnastics 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - -Soccer 1985-1986, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - -Squash 1986-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - -Swimming & Diving 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - -Track & Field 1987-1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - -Volleyball 1986-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - -Miscellaneous Teams & Sports 1988-1990, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Chalking 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Dinner Thank-Yous 1986-1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - First-Year Students 1985-1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hazing Compliance Reports 1987, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - International Students 1985, 1990, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Organizations
    See also Series IX. Committees & Boards-Space Allocation Committee-Student Cultural Organization Space
    - -Black Students Alliance 1985-1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - -Celebrations Dance Company 1989, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - -Debate Society 1986, 1988, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - -Korean Students of Smith 1985, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - -Lesbian Bisexual Alliance 1985, 1991-1995, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
      See also Series XVI. Students-Chalking
    - -Sazanami Club 1989 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - -Service Organizations of Smith (SOS) 1985-1994 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - -Student Government Association (SGA) 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - -Student Government Association (SGA) 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - -Students Against Multiple Sclerosis 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - -United Student Employee Delegation 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - -Miscellaneous 1985-1995 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Parents Newsletter Mailings 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Presidential Interns 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Presidential Interns 1989-1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Publications 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Senior Class 1985-1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Senior Class Gifts 1986-1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Student Activity Fee 1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Student Unrest
    - -Coke Boycott 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - -Concerned Students of All Colors 1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - -Financial Aid (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - -Diversity Meetings with Student Groups 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - -Racism 1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - -South Africa (Box 3)
      See Series IV. Admin. Issues-South Africa-Student Protest
    - -Miscellaneous 1987-1993 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- SERIES XVIII. PHOTOGRAPHS, (1 document box / 0.4 linear feet)
  The photographs in this series document many of the events and activities described in the printed material.
  Additional photographs may be found in the Smith College Archives collections which document specific events, such as Honorary Degree presentations, Ivy Day and Commencement.
  - Portraits ca. 1985-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Portraits Contact Sheets ca. 1985-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alumnae ca. 1985-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Family undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Inauguration
    - -Pictures with MMD 29 Sep 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - -General, without MMD 29 Sep 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Non-Smith Speaking Engagements ca. 1985-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Smith Events ca. 1985-1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Students ca. 1985-1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Teaching 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Contact Sheets ca. 1985-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous ca. 1985-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)